Hiba Abbas Al-Shammary

West Chester, PA 19380

hibaalshammary@yahoo.com | HA920760@wcupa.edu

(610)905-8381

No work visa required

My Website Resume: https://hiba1983.github.io/MyPortfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full- Stack Web Developer / UI Designer with M.sc in Computer Science from West Chester University of Pennsylvania (Graduation May 2022). have ability to build a Web presence from concept, navigation, layout, and programming to UI. worked in a different jobs field that make me have a different experience and enjoyed taking complex problems and find a simple solution to solve it, always strives to write an elegant & efficient code in any program languages will be, ability to write a well-designed, testable, efficient code using current best practices in Web development. Flexibility to learn more languages and training on different codes, working lonely and within group.

Classes covered the following topic:

- Computer Programming (Grade A)
- Intro web Developer (Grade B+)
- Intro Data Structure. (Grade A)
- Foundations CSC (Grade A-)
- Data Structures (Grade A)
- Networks Data Com. (Grade A)
- Advanced Seminar (Grade A)

- Anal of Algthms. (Grade B-)
- Security (Grade B+)
- R Language (Grade B+)
- Topic in web tech. (Grade A)
- Prog Languages (Grade A)
- Internship in CSC (Grade A)

Development languages:

Java, JavaScript, typescript, python, C++, C, Haskell, R & Currently C#.

Frontend:

React, Angular, Angular Material, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, AJAX, Rx JS.

Development application, framework, Version Control & Testing:

MS Visual Studio, Visual Basic, Atom, GitHub, TFS, Postman, Wireshark, Studio 3T, Notepad++, Windows, Linux, JIRA, MS team, currently working on AWS & Azura Cloud certification.

Backend:

MVC5, .Net Core, web API, Node API, .Net Framework, Entity framework.

Databases:

MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB.

Have knowledge of modern UI frameworks such as Angular.JS and React.

Good knowledge of computer hardware, CPU, RAM, Hard Drive Disk, motherboards, etc.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Computer Science, GPA: 3.66, West Chester University of Pennsylvania, West Chester, PA Graduated May 2022

Web Technology CERTIF, GPA :3.8, West Chester University of Pennsylvania, West Chester, PA **May 2020**

Full-Stack Web Developer CERTIF, Udemy Web Development Courses July 2020

B.Sc. Computer Science, GPA:2.9, University of Baghdad, Baghdad, Iraq **Sep 2005**

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

- ***** Create Website Using Bootstrap
 - Successfully design business catalog website using Bootstrap Library using (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, Node, React, MongoDB)

• The project covered the principle for the design, development, and deployment of a website. Link: https://hiba1983.github.io/FirstWebSiteUsingBootstrap/.

***** Web Development

Build a Social Network Website and a Business Catalog Website.
 Successfully design business catalog website using Bootstrap Library using (HTML, CSS)
 The project covered the principle for the design, development, and deployment of a website.
 Link: https://hiba1983.github.io/MyFirstProject/.

Create Play with Drum Webpage using JAVASCRIPT.
 The project covered the principle for the design adding some images with sound and deployment of a website.

Link: https://hiba1983.github.io/PlayingWithDrum/.

 Create Play with Dice Game, design this website using (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT) by Refreshing the webpage, this project covered JAVASCRIPT mathematical power.
 The project covered the principle for the design, development, and deployment of a website. Link: https://hiba1983.github.io/Dice/.

❖ MEAN (MongoDB, Express JS, AngularJS and Node.js) Architecture

- Build a Social Network Website and a Business Catalog Website.
- Understand the basic principles and structure about the Node.js architecture.
- Become familiar with the state of the arts in web technologies.
- Learn the concepts of Single-Page Application (SPA) development.
- Increased my understanding of software engineering practices such as refactoring code, and how to adapt them to my programming style.

❖ Networks and Data Communications (Java or Python programming required)

- Become familiar with data communication and networking technologies.
- Understand the basic principle of communication protocol layers.
- Learn the concept of network programming Using Python.
- The project deepened my knowledge of programming especially object orientation.

❖ Introduction to Data Structures (Algorithms and their application using C++)

- Learn the definitions, implementations, and applications of the most basic data Structures used in computer science.
- The concept of abstract data type is introduced and reinforced by the object concept of C++.
- Includes algorithm analyses, data structure, heuristic search algorithm, evolutionary computation such as genetic algorithm and their derivative.

❖ Programming Languages (Haskell language)

- Understand languages with in the functional, declarative, and object-oriented paradigms Such as Common Lisp, ML, Prolog, Clos, rather than the familiar imperative paradigm.
- Learn the basics of programming language theory.

***** Computer Programming

- Build a Java program to Store and Study the Titanic dataset.
- Successfully Build a Titanic Java Program from a comma separated text file (.csv).
- Understand the principles of algorithmic problem solving are introduced using the Java language.
- Learn the techniques which involve elementary data and control structures.

❖ Scientific Programming and Graphics Using R

- Learn R programming.
- Become familiar with scientific programming using numeric methods.
- Learn graphics packages.

Create/ Update Company Website

- Build a Business Catalog Website with location map.
- Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript & PHP.
- The project covered the principle for the design, development, and deployment of a website. Link: https://hiba1983.github.io/NEI website/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Network Operations Specialist II, NEI Benefits Plan, Newtown square, PA May 2021 – Present

- Manage, Build, Maintain and Organized the Data and daily Mails.
- Documentation, and Record keeping, Attention to detail in problem-solving.
- Implementation, integration, troubleshooting, and evolution of complex system architectures in tiered environments.
- Monitoring systems hardware and recommending necessary upgrades.
- Accomplish daily assignments in support of team initiatives.
- Electronic workflow management system to resolve customer incidents.
- Training on OnBase by Hyland Software (Important Business contents).

Teacher Assistant, Chester Country Intermediate Unit, West Chester, PA

Aug 2018 – May 2021

- Help teacher, recordkeeping, prepared power point presentations.
- Write letter and send them to appropriate bodies, send and receive incoming mails.
- Manage technology class like Videos for Mini-lessons and Live Videos.

Volunteer, CCIU & ESS, PA

Aug 2016 - Aug 2018

- Providing instruction and managing classroom environments in absence of the regular teacher.
- Prepared power point presentations for the teacher.
- Manage technology class like Videos for Mini-lessons and Live Videos.

Manger Assistant, Force10UAE, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Apr 2008 - Aug 2012

- Support Manager by provided a clerical support to company employees, copying, faxing, and filing document.
- Communicated with customers via phone and email to confirm deliveries and respond to inquiries.
- Responded to emails and other correspondence to facilitate communication and enhance business processes.
- Manage technology for the meetings.

Office Administrator, Ministry of Electricity, Baghdad, Iraq

Aug 2006 - Aug 2008

- Manage documentation, and Record keeping, Attention to details.
- Installing and configuring new a hardware.
- Problem-solving techniques to resolve issues quickly and effectively.
- Developed good communication and time-management skills as well as broadening me leadership ability.

Data Entry, Al-Warka Bank, Baghdad, Iraq

Sep 2005 – Aug 2006

• Enter, maintain, and organized the daily data, Documentation, and Record keeping.

- Managed agendas and calendars, boosting productivity and improving organizational initiative.
- Verifying accuracy and sorting information to prepare source data for computer.
- Reviewing data, correcting any incompatibilities, and checking output.